Contact

4753 Apple Tree Cmn Livermore, CA 94551 7756889650 (Home) patrickd79@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/patrick-denney-bsn-cen-40518314 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Critical Care

ICU

Critical Thinking

Certifications

Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN®)

BLS

PALS

Neonatal Resuscitation Program

Patrick Denney BSN, CEN

Student Software Developer (Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS) Livermore, California

Summary

Currently a student in the Bachelor of Science in Software Development at WGU. Expected Grad 2021.

Skilled in basic Java (Still learning, Level 14 at CodeGym.) Skilled in HTML, CSS, and Javascript for web development. Skilled in Responsive web design.

Experience with using Python, SQL, and Excel for data analysis Certified Emergency Nurse Specialization(CEN) from BCEN 5+ years experience in Emergency Nursing.

4+ years experience in Nursing Management/Supervision 15+ years experience as an ICU and ED RN.

5+ years experience in Neurosurgical/Trauma ICU.

5+ years experience in Cardiac ICU including 2+ years CV Surgery ICU.

Experience

Kaiser Permanente

Administrative Nursing Supervisor and Assistant Nurse Manager ICU October 2016 - June 2020 (3 years 9 months)

Fremont, CA

As an Administrative Nursing Supervisor I facilitate efficient throughput and delivery of safe patient care. Ensure proper staffing and allocation of resources for the Nursing staff. As Assistant Nurse Manager of the ICU, I managed the day to day operations of the ICU. I assured resources were available and provided staff development opportunities. I had to resign due to childcare responsibilities and lack of adequate childcare available during the Covid-19 pandemic, to allow my wife to continue working full-time from home. I am also using this time to complete my BS in Software Development Degree.

Marin General Hospital

Charge Nurse Emergency Department and ICU Nurse (Level III Trauma Center)

October 2011 - July 2016 (4 years 10 months)

Greenbrae, California

I was hired as a Charge Nurse in the Emergency Department after working as a travel Nurse in the ED. I managed throughput and allocated resources as needs arose in the ED. I also acted as a resource to the staff nurses in the ED, and assured safe and effective care patients of the ED. I transferred to the ICU after approximately 1.5 years, where I provided care to Trauma, Neurosurgical, Cardiac, and Medical-Surgical ICU patients. I utilized ICP monitoring devices, and assisted with their insertion. I also cared for fresh post operative CV surgery patients.

St. Joseph Health Emergency Room Nurse (Level II Trauma Center) December 2014 - February 2016 (1 year 3 months)

Santa Rosa Memorial Hospital

Began here as a per diem RN in the Emergency Department in Dec 2014.

I provided care mainly in the Trauma and Cardiac specialty care areas of the ED. I also assisted less experienced RNs in the ED as a resource. After 10 months, I transitioned to the role of Relief House Supervisor in October 2015, where I managed the operations of the Hospital in the absence of Upper Management during the off hours of operation. I responded to any situations requiring supervision and assured adequate staffing and resource availability to the nursing staff.

Northern Inyo Community Hospital Staff Registered Nurse ICU August 2009 - April 2013 (3 years 9 months) Bishop, CA

I was hired as an ICU RN after 2 contracts as a travel nurse (non-consecutively). I began as a staff RN in the ICU, but frequently floated to the Emergency Department as needed. I was also a de facto charge nurse of the ICU in the absence of our Manager. I was even left as acting Manager when the Formal Manager was out of the country

for an extended period of time (1 month). I was left in charge of personnel onboarding and maintaining operations of the unit.

Emerald Health Services
Travel Nurse (Trauma ICU, Level II Trauma Center)
December 2010 - March 2011 (4 months)
Riverside County Regional Medical Center ICU

I completed a travel contract at this facility on a leave of absence from Northern Inyo Hospital for the 3 months. I took this assignment to keep my skills sharp, as Northern Inyo Hospital had very low incidence of major trauma patients. I felt it was necessary to work in a high acuity Trauma Center to refresh myself with current practices. I returned to Northern Inyo Hospital immediately after completion of the contract. This is also a teaching facility.

Emerald Health Services

1 year 2 months

Northern Inyo Hospital, Bishop, CA. Travel RN (ICU, ED) October 2008 - January 2009 (4 months)

Northern Inyo Hospital, Bishop, CA

Worked as a travel nurse in the ICU. This was my second contract at this facility. I provided all necessary critical care to ICU patients in the hospital. I also frequently floated to the ED as needed. I am equally comfortable and competent in both areas.

Twin Cities Community Hospital, Templeton, CA. Travel Nurse ICU June 2008 - September 2008 (4 months)

Twin Cities Community Hospital, Templeton, CA

Completed a travel nurse contract in the ICU in this community hospital. This was my second contract at this facility. This is a 10 bed MSICU with medium acuity Cardia and Trauma patients.

Northern Inyo Hospital, Bishop, CA. Travel RN (ICU, ED) April 2008 - July 2008 (4 months)

Northern Inyo Hospital, Bishop, CA

Worked as a travel nurse in the ICU. I provided all necessary critical care to ICU patients in the hospital. I also frequently floated to the ED as needed. I am equally comfortable and competent in both areas.

Marin General Hospital, Greenbrae, CA. Travel RN Emergency Department

December 2007 - March 2008 (4 months)

Marin General Hospital, Greenbrae, CA

Completed a contract as a Travel Nurse in the Emergency Department. This is a Level III Trauma Center with a Cardio-Thoracic Surgery Program. I provided all levels of care to the patients in the ED and was utilized extensively for my Critical Care experience.

On Assignment

1 year 5 months

Banner Lassen Medical Center, Susanville, CA. Travel RN Emergency Department

September 2007 - December 2007 (4 months)

Banner Lassen Medical Center, Susanville, CA

Completed a contract as a Travel Nurse in the Emergency Department. I provided all needed care to patients in the Critical Access Hospital in Rural California.

Fremont-Rideout Health System, Marysville, CA. Travel RN ICU February 2007 - September 2007 (8 months)

Rideout Health, Marysville, CA

Completed 3 consecutive travel contracts at this facility in the MSICU and CVICU. I was floated between and both ICUs and frequently cared for 2nd day post op CV Surgery patients.

Renown Regional Medical Center, Reno, NV. Travel RN Trauma ICU August 2006 - February 2007 (7 months)

Renown Regional Medical Center, Reno, NV

Competed 2 consecutive Travel Nurse contracts in the Trauma ICU at this Level II Trauma Center. I provided care for all levels of Trauma patients. I had extensive experience with Neurosurgical patients (traumatic and non-traumatic). This is a very high acuity unit and all facets of trauma and critical care nursing are necessary to operate in the unit. This is also a teaching facility

Respond Medical Staffing

St. Vincent's Hospital, Birmingham, AL. Travel RN Emergency Department

May 2006 - August 2006 (4 months)

St. Vincent's Hospital, Birmingham, AL

I was a Local Contract RN in the ED in this Urban ED, I provided care for all manner of ill and injured patients. I also was elevated to Charge Nurse on occasions when needed, as I was one of the most experienced Critical Care/ Emergency RNs working there at the time.

Access Nurses

Madera Community Hospital, Madera, CA. Travel RN ICU January 2006 - April 2006 (4 months)

Madera Community Hospital, Madera, CA

Completed a contract as a Travel RN in the ICU in this mid-sized community hospital. This was providing care to mid to high acuity general MSICU patients.

On Assignment

Contra Costa County Regional Medical Center, Martinez, CA. Travel RN ICU/SCU

October 2005 - January 2006 (4 months)

Contra Costa County Regional Medical Center, Martinez, CA

Completed a travel contract in the ICU of this Mid-sized County Medical Center in the ICU. I provided care for all types of mid to high-acuity ICU patients. This is also a teaching facility.

Respond Medical Staffing

Princeton Baptist Medical Center, Birmingham, AL.Travel RN August 2005 - October 2005 (3 months)

Princeton Baptist Medical Center, Birmingham, AL

I worked as a Contract RN in this very busy, very high acuity inner-city ICU. This was specifically a Surgical ICU. Our patients almost 30% CRRT dependent for some amount of time during their stay. This is also a teaching facility.

InteliStaf

Shelby Baptist Medical Center, Alabaster, AL. Travel RN Emergency Department

May 2005 - August 2005 (4 months)

Shelby Baptist Medical Center, Alabaster, AL

Worked as a Contract RN in the Step-Down Unit in this mid-sized Community Hospital. Very high acuity for a SDU. We often had 5-6 patients. Many of the patients were on trach/vent.

Emerald Health Services

Twin Cities Community Hospital, Templeton, CA. Travel RN ICU January 2005 - April 2005 (4 months)

Twin Cities Community Hospital, Templeton, CA

Completed a travel nurse contract in the ICU in this community hospital. This is a 10 bed MSICU with medium acuity Cardia and Trauma patients.

Access Nurses

7 months

Los Alamitos Medical Center, Los Alamitos, CA. Travel RN ICU October 2004 - January 2005 (4 months)

Los Alamitos Medical Center, Los Alamitos, CA

Completed a travel nurse contract in the ICU at this mid-sized Community Hospital. Patient population included many Neurosurgical patients. There was frequent utilization of ICP monitoring.

Victor Valley Community Hospital, Victorville, CA. Travel RN ICU July 2004 - October 2004 (4 months)

Victor Valley Community Hospital, Victorville, CA

Completed a travel nurse contract in the ICU in this community hospital. This is a 10 bed MSICU with medium acuity Cardia and Trauma patients.

East Alabama Medical Center 3 years 4 months Staff Registered Nurse (ICU, ED) May 2003 - July 2004 (1 year 3 months) Opelika, AL

This was my first job as an RN out of school. I began in the ICU, which is a 16 bed MSICU/Trauma ICU. The facility was a Level III Trauma Center due to lack of Neurosurgery services, otherwise functioned as Level II Trauma Center. I also cross-trained and floated to the ED, where I was able to gain important skills in Trauma Nursing.

Paramedic

April 2001 - June 2003 (2 years 3 months) Opelika, AL

Worked as a Paramedic, where I was in command of an ALS unit and a rescue team for that shift. Provided all needed Pre-hospital ALS and Trauma care to patients. I was also proficient and utilized heavy rescue techniques as needed (Jaws of Life, water rescue, trench rescue, high-angle rescue,)

City of Lanett Fire and EMS
Firefighter/Paramedic
October 2000 - June 2003 (2 years 9 months)
Lanett, AL

Worked as a Firefighter/Paramedic. Performed emergency medical, rescue, and fire suppression operations. Qualified in Firefighter I, Apparatus Operator (Engine and Aerial), Hazardous Materials Technician Level, and Heavy/ Technical Rescue.

Alexander City Fire Department Firefighter/Paramedic August 1998 - April 2001 (2 years 9 months)

Alexander City, AL

Worked as a Firefighter/Paramedic. Performed emergency medical, rescue, and fire suppression operations. Qualified in Firefighter I, Apparatus Operator (Engine and Aerial), Hazardous Materials Technician Level, and Heavy/ Technical Rescue.

Education

Western Governors University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Software Development · (2020 - 2021)

Western Governors University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Registered Nursing/Registered

Nurse · (2016 - 2018)

Udemy Alumni

Certification, Modern Javascript from the Beginning · (2019 - 2020)

Udacity

Nanodegree in Programing for Data Science , Data Science · (2019 - 2019)

Southern Union State Community College

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2001 - 2003)